<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Software Developer</title><link>https://knage.net/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Software Developer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 15:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://knage.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Raspberry Pi as TimeMachine and NAS</title><link>https://knage.net/2023/02/raspberry-pi-timemachine-and-nas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://knage.net/2023/02/raspberry-pi-timemachine-and-nas/</guid><description>This post covers configuring a Raspberry Pi 4 B as a TimeMachine and NAS Server.
Raspberry Pi offers a great guide on how to setup a NAS server (that also supports TimeMachine) using openmediavault.
This post however takes a different approach, where you will configure Samba manually to make your TimeMachine and NAS available on your network.
This is part 3 of 4 in a mini series where we will configure a headless Raspberry Pi 4 B as an efficient home server, capable of hosting Network Attached Storage (NAS), TimeMachine and Plex Media Server.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Backup</title><link>https://knage.net/2023/02/raspberry-pi-backup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://knage.net/2023/02/raspberry-pi-backup/</guid><description>This post covers implementing an effective backup strategy for your Raspberry Pi
Having a plan for how to recover when things break down is essential when you depend on your server.
This is part 2 of 4 in a mini series where we will configure a headless Raspberry Pi 4 B as an efficient home server, capable of hosting Network Attached Storage (NAS), TimeMachine and Plex Media Server.
Through this series we will also look at how we can make automatic backups to keep uor data safe.</description></item><item><title>Headless Raspberry Pi Server</title><link>https://knage.net/2023/01/raspberry-pi-headless-setup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://knage.net/2023/01/raspberry-pi-headless-setup/</guid><description>This post covers setting up a headless Raspberry Pi 4 B from scratch.
Raspberry Pi has excellent documentation on how to setup and configure a Raspberry Pi. This post leans on the official documentation and focus on the parts that are essential to get up and running.
This is part 1 of 4 in a mini series where we will configure a headless Raspberry Pi 4 B as an efficient home server, capable of hosting Network Attached Storage (NAS), TimeMachine and Plex Media Server.</description></item></channel></rss>